I'm here with a running back Ty
Chandler, the newest member of the New
Orleans Saints. Ty, when you were in
this free agency process, what made you
want to decide to come here with the
Saints?
You know,
love what Coach Moore is doing with the
organization, his
the creativity he brings to the game and
everything involved in it. I thought it
was a great fit after discussing with my
agent and he did a great job in helping
me make the decision, but I'm [snorts]
looking forward to getting to know the
city, getting to know my teammates and
looking forward to competing. How much
do you know about the city of New
Orleans and their fan base?
You know, not too much.
Great food. So excited about that.
Excited to get out and get back to the
community
and get to know get to know the city and
take it all in.
What are your thoughts on the Superdome
and having that be your home stadium?
I love it. I love it.
I heard it's a great atmosphere, great
place to play.
They bring the energy, so that's
that's always exciting and
a beautiful part of the game when you
got the fans behind you, the support and
the love. So
looking forward to experiencing it.
You started your collegiate career at
Tennessee. Your dad played running back
at Ole Miss. So you have some deep SEC
ties. We're in SEC country now.
So do you have anybody that you're
pulling for?
Nobody specific I'm pulling for. Like
you said, my dad
played for Ole Miss, so I grew up
watching Ole Miss football.
I got the chance the great opportunity
to go to University of Tennessee and so
I'm always supporting the SEC and look
forward to them playing and watching the
games, but I can't say I'll pull for
anybody specific. Fair enough. Okay.
Yeah, you can't really pick sides down
here.
A lot of LSU. I will just tell you that.
>> [laughter]
[snorts and sighs]
>> So when you come in as a running back
and your fit here with the team, are we
going to see you in that return game? Is
that something you're interested in?
That's something I'm always interested
in
looking forward to getting
to to explore that more. So I would
always be open to that.
Looking forward to competing with the
running back room as well and absorbing
the knowledge of the game and learning
from different guys like Alvin and
Travis and all those great guys in the
running back room. So looking forward to
that, looking forward to competing and
making the most of the opportunity.
Something that stands out about your
game is your speed. How do you utilize
that in the your style of play as a
back?
Speed has always been a weapon for me.
Something I'm constantly working on,
working to improve, but
and I look forward to bringing that to
the game, but every aspect of my game
I'm just constantly trying to improve on
and and get better at taking the next
step and and continue to develop as a
player,
>> [snorts]
>> just as a man and
absorbing knowledge from the game and
being able to use that on the field.
You were drafted in 2022. How has your
game grown or maybe even you on and off
the field as a person?
Just learning,
having a chance to see the game from a
different point of view, perspective and
just taking in a bunch of wisdom and
knowledge that I've gained over the
years and incorporating that into my
game. So
catching the ball out the backfield,
just being an explosive player and
making plays even on special teams when
it counts. So
just
taking all that in, developing and
continuing to grow and absorb more
knowledge of the game, becoming a
student of the game.
Okay, so in 211 career touches, you have
never fumbled. And I do not I'm not
going to wood, like I do not want to be
in trouble for jinxing that at all, but
that is an amazing stat. So congrats on
that. What is something else the fans
have to know about you as a player?
Have to know about me as a player?
I I give my all.
You know, it's something that you dream
about growing up as a kid and just
it's a blessing to just be able to have
the opportunity to play this game. So
that's what I bring to the table. I'm
going to work hard
and just go compete when I'm out there
on that field. It
means the world and
like I said, it's just a blessing to be
able to have this opportunity.
So
that's it. All right, Ty, off the field,
what what kind of personality are we
getting? Man, I'm a country boy at
heart.
Usually out in the woods. I love
fishing.
I grew up riding horses, training horses
and
riding four wheelers, doing those type
of activities. So I'm out outdoors
person at heart,
but love getting out in the community,
having a chance to give back and just
looking to be a blessing to somebody
else. Why is that so important to you?
That's how I was raised. My grandma kind
of instilled that in me and
she told me to pray my way through it.
So just just spreading love, breathing
life into other people and
spreading positivity.
That's great. I'm excited to welcome you
to the Saints. We look forward to seeing
you here and on the field soon. There
are some other country boys that you're
going to be able to get along with just
fine. Yes, ma'am. I look forward to it.